The biggest comedy ever assembled!
Robots is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Chris Wedge.
Rodney Copperbottom is a young robot inventor who dreams of making the world a
better place, until the evil Ratchet takes over Bigweld Industries.
Now, Rodney's dreams – and those of his friends –
are in danger of becoming obsolete.
Rodney Copperbottom (voice), played by Ewan McGregor.
Cappy (voice), played by Halle Berry.
Ratchet (voice), played by Greg Kinnear.
Bigweld (voice), played by Mel Brooks.
Crank (voice), played by Drew Carey.
Piper (voice), played by Amanda Bynes.
Robots is a 2005 American animated science fiction comedy film directed by Chris Wedge
and written by David Lindsay-Abaire, Lowell Ganz and Babaloo Mandel.
Produced by 20th Century Fox Animation and Blue Sky Studios, it stars the voices of Ewan McGregor,
Halle Berry, Greg Kinnear, Mel Brooks, Amanda Bynes, Drew Carey and Robin Williams.
The story follows an ambitious inventor robot named Rodney Copperbottom, who seeks to work for his
idol Bigweld's company in Robot City, but discovers a plot by its new leader Phineas T.
Ratchet and his mother to forcibly upgrade the city's populace and
eradicate struggling robots, known as "outmodes".
Development of the film began in 2000, following a failed attempt by Wedge and children's
author William Joyce to adapt Joyce's 1993 children's book Santa Calls.
They instead decided to create an original story based on robots.
The project was approved by executive producer Chris
Meledandri in 2001 and production began the next year.
Robots premiered at the Mann Village Theatre in Westwood, Los Angeles, on March 6, 2005,
and was released in the United States on March 11 by 20th Century Fox.
The film was praised by critics for its humor, animation, and performances,
while its story and characters were deemed somewhat formulaic.
The film was commercially successful, grossing $262.5 million
worldwide against a $75–80 million budget.
A sequel was discussed but never produced due to the studio
shifting focus to its flagship franchise, Ice Age.
The film explores themes of inventor, businessman, villain, robot, dishonesty.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.